<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>educational on Dor Ben Dor</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/educational/</link><description>Recent content in educational on Dor Ben Dor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/educational/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Midbaryom</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/midbaryom/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/midbaryom/</guid><description>Instead of cages, a 120 acre of savannah, teeming with life.
As a Game Designer you often than not - an entratainer. You craft expreiences that alleviate fun. That is why Midbaryom is a very special project, in size, purpose and ethical values.
A zoo is to be rebuilt as natural 120 acre savannanah, in the heart of the Israeli Negev. This Safari is not only meant to display the animals as some kind of trophies, but to actualy educate the people about the importance of wildelife perservance and to create empathy with the animals.</description></item><item><title>My First Animal</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/my-first-animal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/my-first-animal/</guid><description>A clean educational experience for toddlers about animals and the sound they make
The game includes 7 scenes with 26 interactable animals and objects. The game&amp;rsquo;s input is intuitive and designed specifically for toddlers - only swipe left or right. No cumbersome UI that children can missclick.
PLATFORM
Mobile (Android)
ROLE
Game Designer | Unity Developer
GENRE
Educational, Kids
STATUS
Published
PUBLISHER
Self Published</description></item><item><title>Brainiac</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/brainniac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/brainniac/</guid><description>Better! Faster! Smarter! Brainiac is a powerful tool for your mind and a pleasing one for your soul.
Brainiac is all about improving your cognitive skills while having fun doing so. Featuring five different exercises, a solid progression system and a daily routine for players to utilize. As players advance and complete their daily goals, they encounter new difficulty elements in the same exercises, effectively keeping the game alive for longer and presenting the player with a true and natural progression curve.</description></item><item><title>Neuroderm</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/neuroderm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/neuroderm/</guid><description>Make your way through obstacles and learn a couple of things while at it!
This flappy bird look-a-like is teaching us about the problems of current Parkinson medication and how they might be solved. The real pride of this project on my side, beyond the tight schedule, is the music and SFX that I composed 🙂. The game was developed over a 24 hour preriod!
listen! PLATFORM PC</description></item></channel></rss>