<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>puzzle on Dor Ben Dor</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/puzzle/</link><description>Recent content in puzzle on Dor Ben Dor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/puzzle/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Party Cat</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/party-cat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/party-cat/</guid><description>Swipe your way around the house and clean it all up!
Remember Color Maze? You have to swipe your avatar around to fill the screen. Well, the level design on this game was even harder. The demand was to make the board smaller and the levels more visually appealing. This meant that the actual puzzle might be compromised. But in the end I used the same techniques to create challenging levels even on smaller scales.</description></item><item><title>Color Maze</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/colormaze/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/colormaze/</guid><description>Swipe! Swipe! Swipe to fill the screen with bright colors!
This project was challenging because of the overtly simple core mechanics, which at first didn’t allow intricate level design. In addition, the publishers didn’t want any levels where the player could actually get stuck, so a careful thought was given to how to build the levels that in the beginning they would introduce the mechanics and later on could actualy pose a bit of challenge.</description></item><item><title>Bow &amp; Arrow</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/bow-and-arrow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/bow-and-arrow/</guid><description>“Hear ye! Hear ye! The king is looking for the best archer in the land! Are you up for a challenge of Bow &amp;amp; Arrow?
This was so much fun to make and one of my first experiences with VR. The game feels intuitive to play and player skill increases in a steep curve.
PLATFORM
Virtual Reality (HTC Vive, Oculus)
ROLE
Sole Developer
GENRE
Arcade, Puzzle
STATUS
Private Buyer - designated for VR arcade</description></item></channel></rss>