<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>unity on Dor Ben Dor</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/unity/</link><description>Recent content in unity on Dor Ben Dor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Scriptable Holders</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/articles/unity/scriptableholders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/articles/unity/scriptableholders/</guid><description>Preface Scriptable Objects (SOs) are awesome. It&amp;rsquo;s been said before, it will be said in the future and currently, many Unity devs use them to architect their code and write great games. But (you knew this was coming), they are still a tight coupling to the unity engine - Scriptable Objects only make sense inside the unity framework. I noticed most Unity devs don&amp;rsquo;t give a f*** about this, but I do give plenty.</description></item><item><title>GaW - Heroes of Might &amp; Magic</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/game-a-week/homm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/game-a-week/homm/</guid><description>Heroes of Might &amp;amp; Magic III is one of my all time favourite games. It proposes 4 core systesms (heroes, castles, exploration and combat) each feeding each other to create a hollistic and compelling gameplay. Trying to imitate it in one week was both challenging and incredibly fun.
.button-link { background-color: #008CBA; color: white; padding: 10px 20px; text-align: center; text-decoration: none; display: inline-block; font-size: 16px; border-radius: 5px; } .button-link:hover { background-color: #005f6b; } Play the Prototype Tech Stack Unity 6.</description></item><item><title>Warriors Rise To Glory</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/warriors-rise-to-glory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/warriors-rise-to-glory/</guid><description>In this rogue-lite turn-based RPG, you create a bloodline of gladiators, fight online with or against your friends in the arena, decide the fate of your fallen rivals, and bring honor, wealth, and the spoils of war to improve your legacy.
PLATFORM PC
ROLE Unity Developer
GENRE RPG, RougueLite, Turn Based, Strategy
STATUS Published - You can play the game here
PUBLISHER Gavra Games</description></item><item><title>Phantom Beasts</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/canceled/phantom-beasts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/canceled/phantom-beasts/</guid><description>Unleash your inner beast and shoot your way through a dystopian city in this deadly 2.5D side scroller. Gun down your enemies and use your phantoms to get out of tough situations. /* Basic styling for readability */ table { width: 80%; margin: 20px auto; border-collapse: collapse; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; } th, td { padding: 12px 15px; text-align: center; border: 1px solid #ddd; } th { background-color: #add8e6; /* Light blue color */ font-weight: bold; } tr:nth-child(even) { background-color: #f9f9f9; } .</description></item><item><title>Summoners Royale</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/summoners-royale/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/summoners-royale/</guid><description>A Real time PvP strategy game for android (web3), empowering players with strategic decisions in lightweight tactical battles. Overview Summoners Royale is truly a fascinating project. Resurrected from the dead (previously known as United Legends), Summoners Royale made deep impactful changes to its design to create a new gameplay expreince that could match the spirit of the company that produced it and to become a unique skill based game set against the agressive (and mostly disgusting) models of the web3 gaming.</description></item><item><title>Treasure Hunt</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/hackathons/treasure-hunt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/hackathons/treasure-hunt/</guid><description>*1v1 multiplayer game in which each player hides his treasure, and tries to find his opponents.* Overview It was SO-MUCH-FUN making this game (excuse the all-caps but I really mean it) in the 2021 Global Game Jam. In just 48 hours (- kids) we managed, me and my buddy Gilad, to create this beautiful, simple, fun game. What I love about this design is its simplicity and elegance. A Core mechanic, finding the opponents treasure with radars and nothing more.</description></item><item><title>Neuroderm</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/neuroderm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/neuroderm/</guid><description>Make your way through obstacles and learn a couple of things while at it!
This flappy bird look-a-like is teaching us about the problems of current Parkinson medication and how they might be solved. The real pride of this project on my side, beyond the tight schedule, is the music and SFX that I composed 🙂. The game was developed over a 24 hour preriod!
listen! PLATFORM PC</description></item><item><title>VoX</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/exercises/vox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/exercises/vox/</guid><description>Race! VoX is a unique VR arcade game where you’ll try to out best yourself and your friends. Collect coins, drift and stay on track!
If you worked with VR, guess you could spot the challenge here: How do you handle motion sickness and racing in VR? It’s hard, but doable. Wrapping google anti motion sickness SDK with unity scripts while also improving on that SDK proved to be a viable solution.</description></item><item><title>Bow &amp; Arrow</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/bow-and-arrow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/bow-and-arrow/</guid><description>“Hear ye! Hear ye! The king is looking for the best archer in the land! Are you up for a challenge of Bow &amp;amp; Arrow?
This was so much fun to make and one of my first experiences with VR. The game feels intuitive to play and player skill increases in a steep curve.
PLATFORM
Virtual Reality (HTC Vive, Oculus)
ROLE
Sole Developer
GENRE
Arcade, Puzzle
STATUS
Private Buyer - designated for VR arcade</description></item><item><title>Project Name</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/templates/projecttemplate/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/templates/projecttemplate/</guid><description>description or fluff here /* Basic styling for readability */ table { width: 80%; margin: 20px auto; border-collapse: collapse; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; } th, td { padding: 12px 15px; text-align: center; border: 1px solid #ddd; } th { background-color: #add8e6; /* Light blue color */ font-weight: bold; } tr:nth-child(even) { background-color: #f9f9f9; } .button-link { background-color: #008CBA; color: white; padding: 10px 20px; text-align: center; text-decoration: none; display: inline-block; font-size: 16px; border-radius: 5px; } .</description></item></channel></rss>