<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>android on Dor Ben Dor</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/android/</link><description>Recent content in android on Dor Ben Dor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Color Maze</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/colormaze/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/colormaze/</guid><description>Swipe! Swipe! Swipe to fill the screen with bright colors!
This project was challenging because of the overtly simple core mechanics, which at first didn’t allow intricate level design. In addition, the publishers didn’t want any levels where the player could actually get stuck, so a careful thought was given to how to build the levels that in the beginning they would introduce the mechanics and later on could actualy pose a bit of challenge.</description></item><item><title>Project Name</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/drafts/articles/game-design-objective-taxonomy/objective_taxonomy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/drafts/articles/game-design-objective-taxonomy/objective_taxonomy/</guid><description>Objectives will always be the core pillars of what makes a game. Remember, simply playing with something does not mean you&amp;rsquo;re playing a game
Objectives can be categorized by their relation to the MDA aspects: mechanics, dynamics, aesthetics.
mechanics: formal objectives dynamics: goals aesthetics: informal objectives</description></item><item><title>What is a game</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/drafts/articles/game-design-what-is-a-game/whatisagame/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/drafts/articles/game-design-what-is-a-game/whatisagame/</guid><description>How do you define a medium that shapeshifts depending on the participants point of reference? It is a dissonance, that games are impossible to define, but are so easily defined in our minds. Humans certainly understand when they do and when they aren&amp;rsquo;t, playing games.
Defining games is somewhat of a futile persuement. I don&amp;rsquo;t think one defintion can encompass this huge and complex medium. but, the strive for a solution and the road taken to find answers, is more important than the goal.</description></item></channel></rss>