<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>game design on Dor Ben Dor</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/game-design/</link><description>Recent content in game design on Dor Ben Dor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dorbendor.com/tags/game-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Party Cat</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/party-cat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/party-cat/</guid><description>Swipe your way around the house and clean it all up!
Remember Color Maze? You have to swipe your avatar around to fill the screen. Well, the level design on this game was even harder. The demand was to make the board smaller and the levels more visually appealing. This meant that the actual puzzle might be compromised. But in the end I used the same techniques to create challenging levels even on smaller scales.</description></item><item><title>VoX</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/vox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/vox/</guid><description>Race! VoX is a unique VR arcade game where you’ll try to out best yourself and your friends. Collect coins, drift and stay on track!
If you worked with VR, guess you could spot the challenge here: How do you handle motion sickness and racing in VR? It’s hard, but doable. Wrapping google anti motion sickness SDK with unity scripts while also improving on that SDK proved to be a viable solution.</description></item><item><title>Yeti Getaway</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/yeti-getaway/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/yeti-getaway/</guid><description>Endless Runner Casual game for Facebook’s Instant Games (FIG). Avoid being caught! Swipe your Yeti to avoid obstacles and collect powerups, and don’t forget to eat them apples!
Migrated the original game, &amp;ldquo;Yeti Sensation&amp;rdquo;, to Facebook Instant Games. It required a lot of research on the new platform and a deep dive into social mechanics and communication features. You can take a look at the early design process here (the first edit of the doc).</description></item></channel></rss>