<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Dor Ben Dor</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Dor Ben Dor</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game a Week Challenge - Rules</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/game-a-week/rules/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/game-a-week/rules/</guid><description>What is the &amp;ldquo;Game In A Week&amp;rdquo; Challenge? 🕹️ Game in a Week (GaW) is a self-imposed challenge to build a bitching prototype for an existing game (preferably a genre-defining one). It’s an undertaking in which I show that quick prototyping is easy,fun, and can yield great results. I hope both you and I will learn a lot along the way.
Structure 🛠️ We will start by reverse-designing the game. We&amp;rsquo;ll understand what systems comprise gameplay and what needs to be done in terms of code, tech art, and assets.</description></item><item><title>Scriptable Holders</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/articles/unity/scriptableholders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/articles/unity/scriptableholders/</guid><description>Preface Scriptable Objects (SOs) are awesome. It&amp;rsquo;s been said before, it will be said in the future and currently, many Unity devs use them to architect their code and write great games. But (you knew this was coming), they are still a tight coupling to the unity engine - Scriptable Objects only make sense inside the unity framework. I noticed most Unity devs don&amp;rsquo;t give a f*** about this, but I do give plenty.</description></item><item><title>GaW - Heroes of Might &amp; Magic</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/game-a-week/homm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/game-a-week/homm/</guid><description>Heroes of Might &amp;amp; Magic III is one of my all time favourite games. It proposes 4 core systesms (heroes, castles, exploration and combat) each feeding each other to create a hollistic and compelling gameplay. Trying to imitate it in one week was both challenging and incredibly fun.
.button-link { background-color: #008CBA; color: white; padding: 10px 20px; text-align: center; text-decoration: none; display: inline-block; font-size: 16px; border-radius: 5px; } .button-link:hover { background-color: #005f6b; } Play the Prototype Tech Stack Unity 6.</description></item><item><title>Warriors Rise To Glory</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/warriors-rise-to-glory/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/warriors-rise-to-glory/</guid><description>In this rogue-lite turn-based RPG, you create a bloodline of gladiators, fight online with or against your friends in the arena, decide the fate of your fallen rivals, and bring honor, wealth, and the spoils of war to improve your legacy.
PLATFORM PC
ROLE Unity Developer
GENRE RPG, RougueLite, Turn Based, Strategy
STATUS Published - You can play the game here
PUBLISHER Gavra Games</description></item><item><title>Phantom Beasts</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/canceled/phantom-beasts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/canceled/phantom-beasts/</guid><description>Unleash your inner beast and shoot your way through a dystopian city in this deadly 2.5D side scroller. Gun down your enemies and use your phantoms to get out of tough situations. /* Basic styling for readability */ table { width: 80%; margin: 20px auto; border-collapse: collapse; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; } th, td { padding: 12px 15px; text-align: center; border: 1px solid #ddd; } th { background-color: #add8e6; /* Light blue color */ font-weight: bold; } tr:nth-child(even) { background-color: #f9f9f9; } .</description></item><item><title>Summoners Royale</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/summoners-royale/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/summoners-royale/</guid><description>A Real time PvP strategy game for android (web3), empowering players with strategic decisions in lightweight tactical battles. Overview Summoners Royale is truly a fascinating project. Resurrected from the dead (previously known as United Legends), Summoners Royale made deep impactful changes to its design to create a new gameplay expreince that could match the spirit of the company that produced it and to become a unique skill based game set against the agressive (and mostly disgusting) models of the web3 gaming.</description></item><item><title>Midbaryom</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/midbaryom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/midbaryom/</guid><description>Instead of cages, a 120 acre of savannah, teeming with life.
As a Game Designer you often than not - an entratainer. You craft expreiences that alleviate fun. That is why Midbaryom is a very special project, in size, purpose and ethical values.
A zoo is to be rebuilt as natural 120 acre savannanah, in the heart of the Israeli Negev. This Safari is not only meant to display the animals as some kind of trophies, but to actualy educate the people about the importance of wildelife perservance and to create empathy with the animals.</description></item><item><title>My First Animal</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/my-first-animal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/my-first-animal/</guid><description> *A clean educational experience for toddlers about animals and the sound they make* Overview The game includes 7 scenes with 26 interactable animals and objects. The game&amp;rsquo;s input is intuitive and designed specifically for toddlers - only swipe left or right. No cumbersome UI that children can missclick.
**PLATFORM** Mobile (Android)
ROLE
Game Designer | Unity Developer
GENRE
Educational, Kids
STATUS
Published
PUBLISHER
Self Published</description></item><item><title>Treasure Hunt</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/hackathons/treasure-hunt/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/hackathons/treasure-hunt/</guid><description>1v1 multiplayer game in which each player hides his treasure, and tries to find his opponents. /* Basic styling for readability */ table { width: 90%; margin: 20px auto; border-collapse: collapse; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; } th, td { padding: 12px 15px; text-align: center; border: 1px solid #ddd; } th { background-color: #add8e6; /* Light blue color */ font-weight: bold; } tr:nth-child(even) { background-color: #f9f9f9; } .</description></item><item><title>Brainiac</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/brainiac/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/brainiac/</guid><description>Better! Faster! Smarter! Brainiac is a powerful tool for your mind and a pleasing one for your soul.
Brainiac is all about improving your cognitive skills while having fun doing so. Featuring five different exercises, a solid progression system and a daily routine for players to utilize. As players advance and complete their daily goals, they encounter new difficulty elements in the same exercises, effectively keeping the game alive for longer and presenting the player with a true and natural progression curve.</description></item><item><title>Neuroderm</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/neuroderm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/neuroderm/</guid><description>Make your way through obstacles and learn a couple of things while at it!
This flappy bird look-a-like is teaching us about the problems of current Parkinson medication and how they might be solved. The real pride of this project on my side, beyond the tight schedule, is the music and SFX that I composed 🙂. The game was developed over a 24 hour preriod!
listen! PLATFORM PC</description></item><item><title>Party Cat</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/party-cat/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/party-cat/</guid><description>Swipe your way around the house and clean it all up!
Remember Color Maze? You have to swipe your avatar around to fill the screen. Well, the level design on this game was even harder. The demand was to make the board smaller and the levels more visually appealing. This meant that the actual puzzle might be compromised. But in the end I used the same techniques to create challenging levels even on smaller scales.</description></item><item><title>Color Maze</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/colormaze/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/colormaze/</guid><description>Swipe! Swipe! Swipe to fill the screen with bright colors!
This project was challenging because of the overtly simple core mechanics, which at first didn’t allow intricate level design. In addition, the publishers didn’t want any levels where the player could actually get stuck, so a careful thought was given to how to build the levels that in the beginning they would introduce the mechanics and later on could actualy pose a bit of challenge.</description></item><item><title>VoX</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/exercises/vox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/misc/exercises/vox/</guid><description>Race! Race! Race! VoX is a unique VR arcade game where you’ll try to out best yourself and your friends. Collect coins, drift and stay on track! /* Basic styling for readability */ table { width: 90%; margin: 20px auto; border-collapse: collapse; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; } th, td { padding: 12px 15px; text-align: center; border: 1px solid #ddd; } th { background-color: #add8e6; /* Light blue color */ font-weight: bold; } tr:nth-child(even) { background-color: #f9f9f9; } .</description></item><item><title>Bow &amp; Arrow</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/bow-and-arrow/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/bow-and-arrow/</guid><description>“Hear ye! Hear ye! The king is looking for the best archer in the land! Are you up for a challenge of Bow &amp;amp; Arrow?
This was so much fun to make and one of my first experiences with VR. The game feels intuitive to play and player skill increases in a steep curve.
PLATFORM
Virtual Reality (HTC Vive, Oculus)
ROLE
Sole Developer
GENRE
Arcade, Puzzle
STATUS
Private Buyer - designated for VR arcade</description></item><item><title>Yeti Getaway</title><link>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/yeti-getaway/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.dorbendor.com/posts/projects/published/yeti-getaway/</guid><description>Endless Runner Casual game for Facebook’s Instant Games (FIG). Avoid being caught! Swipe your Yeti to avoid obstacles and collect powerups, and don’t forget to eat them apples!
Migrated the original game, &amp;ldquo;Yeti Sensation&amp;rdquo;, to Facebook Instant Games. It required a lot of research on the new platform and a deep dive into social mechanics and communication features. You can take a look at the early design process here (the first edit of the doc).</description></item></channel></rss>